Knowing that all Heaven was backing him up,
Wise Man Christopher moves through the auditorium of The SCOAN,
touching the congregation in the name of Jesus with the corresponding power from Heaven.
As the wise man offers prayer in the power of the Holy Spirit, he encounters a demonic entity
in the life of this young man and commands the fire of the Holy Spirit
to cast the darkness out of his body, soul and spirit.
Let's watch his deliverance.
All over your body you demons - fire in the name of Jesus Christ!
All over your body, in the name of Jesus Christ, fire!
Who are you?
I am the prince of Persia.
All over your body, Holy Ghost fire in the name of Jesus Christ!
You demon.
We stripped him of all his power; we made him naked.
Stand up and talk clearly!
You said, "we".
How many of you and who are you people?
We are a hierarchy.
I come with signs and wonders to fool many.
Yes.
I am the prince of Persia, and what do you want from me?
As the prince of Persia, how do you operate?
I go to houses.
I will kill him.
Yes.
I filled him with anger; I visited him so many times
so that he would commit suicide.
He is bored with life.
He went to his village to pray.
We hooked him because we knew his plan.
His plan is to free the people.
I fooled him into thinking it was time to pray for his people.
We arranged it so he might think it was time for his calling.
He persevered so much to deliver his clan.
As a result of that, he got tired and then started backsliding.
He lost faith.
He knew what the Word of God had told him that
if your faith is as small as a mustard seed, you will move mountains.
But it was a failure; it was programmed.
Since then, we filled him with all kinds of spirits, new things that would trigger his mind,
new things that would make him to be full of unbelief, doubt, fear, pain and grief.
We came through music.
You came through what?
Music!
Yes.
What kind of music?
During the eighties; we called it 'pop and lock'.
We filled his brain with mischief.
He is an artist; the boy is talented.
He can make movies; he draws cartoons.
Yes.
He can paint beautiful things but we distracted him so he would stop painting
and concentrate on something else.
How did you distract him?
He got bored with painting and thought that there was no gain in it.
We told him lies that his painting would take him nowhere.
He decided to join a dance group.
You must have known of the 'Xfellas'.
Yes.
Who else is in this body apart from you?
I am pregnant with him.
I am the queen.
The queen of where?
From the coast.
Who are you?
Queen of where?
From the marine kingdom.
How do you operate as a queen in him?
Through the spirit of lust.
Yes.
We set him up with the wrong people.
He thought he had found life, not knowing that it's either he was working
as an agent or it was to send him deeper into the ocean.
As the spirit of lust, what are the things you have been pushing him to do against his will?
He is the shy type.
He doesn't go about chasing girls or women.
But we have filled him with so much lust and the only way he can be satisfied is by masturbation.
To do what?
Masturbate.
It has killed his plans, his career, his jobs everywhere he went.
It sends him back to start afresh.
He can dance.
He can dance?
Yes. He is a choreographer.
He has helped many to achieve their dreams through dancing.
But I gave him setback.
He will not make it – never.
What are the things you have done to his job as an artist?
How have you been using this as an "avenue" to operate as an evil spirit?
He was meant to use his gift to teach people of the deep things of God,
to share the knowledge of God to the people of the world, to break barriers, to free.
How have you been using this gift?
We twisted his gift.
You twisted his gift?
Yes.
How did you twist his gift?
He was meant to use the gift to lead many to the Kingdom of God but
we have used it to lead many astray.
We used the gift to lure boys and girls, young teenagers, into the kingdom of occult.
Mention the name.
The satanic kingdom, the kingdom of the Persian god.
What are the things you do that initiates those people into your demonic kingdom?
We use them to trick the boys and girls...
What are the tricks?
… to think that they are learning new moves, new steps.
New steps and new moves?
Yes.
But all this is to glorify our kingdom.
Which kingdom?
The marine world.
Does it mean that - if this boy is giving them a new step and a new move,
the sense of that move and step comes from your kingdom?
Yes.
When they move and dance in that way, what will be happening to them?
They get enticed; we make their hearts to love entertainment more than their God.
We steal their hearts...
To where?
... and pull them to join us.
The more they see us, the more they watch us, the more they want to be like us.
How many of them have you captured and initiated all over the world?
How many?
Ten thousand.
Who else is in this body?
His younger sister left him when she was eight years old.
Yes.
She was also from the marine kingdom.
I live inside them.
What form do you take to come to him?
I come through his dreams.
In form of what?
He sees me all the time in his dreams.
We play together; I come in the image of his sister.
Yes.
Since he lost her, he has not been himself.
Who took her?
I killed her.
What have you done to the family?
I set them back from promotion; I quenched it.
Yes.
How did you quench it?
They must not prosper.
What are the things you did in order to quench their promotion, prosperity?
Through dreams, we make them to fornicate in their dreams in the underworld.
When you push them to fornicate as you said, what would be happening to their career and health?
They go backwards; they find it difficult to approach their future.
There is a lady standing next to you; who is she to you?
I don’t know.
I am your mother.
She is playing a prank on you!
You are my son.
It wasn't funny!
Your name is Samuel.
I don’t know.
Samuel, I am your mother.
Who is this man to you?
He is my sister’s son.
Samuel, you are my nephew.
He is on his own; he has his own mission.
What is his mission?
His mission is to free lives also.
Madam, you are very welcome.
Thank you, Man of God.
What can you say about your son and his character?
When he was in primary school, he was very intelligent, bright and scientifically minded.
He would make toys.
I thought he was going to be a scientist.
So, I put him in technical school.
At technical school, they discovered that he was good at drawing portraits of people;
he would draw people exactly the way they were.
He was very good at it.
I thought that was the field he would go into so I encouraged him in that.
After a while, when he reached the higher class, he changed.
He was no longer going to school.
When I sent him to school, at times, he would deviate and go somewhere else.
When I gave him money to pay for his school fees when I was not around,
he would take it, go somewhere else and spend the money.
That made me very angry.
After secondary school, I told him to prepare for an exam but he found it difficult to read.
His attention was removed from reading.
I was worried about that.
I then sent him to a computer school.
He was going there for only three months and he stopped.
He was never able to finish what he started.
I was so worried about that.
It was later revealed that he had the gift of a prophet.
He used to speak as a man of God.
He would tell you everything about yourself, then.
He would heal and deliver people and also preach.
He had a group of people who he would preach to.
After then, all that changed.
He became lukewarm and stopped attending services or fellowships.
I was angry about that.
The way he is dressed now is how he used to dress.
He had so many suits in his wardrobe, then.
But he changed and started looking into the world again.
Some dancers visited him and they wanted him to join their dance group.
I said I didn’t want that because I thought he was going to be a pastor.
I was working towards that.
I said I didn't want it.
But they persisted and he started dancing with them.
It reached the point that he became very good and then they broke up.
He formed his own group and they were doing very well.
I didn’t like it though because he was no longer going to fellowships.
Even when Sunday came, he wouldn't remember it was Sunday.
He would just sleep and not wake up on time.
Even at home, he stopped helping me in the house.
At times, he would be there and I would be sweeping the house.
I would even sweep around his feet and he would just watch me and continue doing whatever he was doing.
While some other children, when they see their parents doing certain things,
they would take over the job and finish it.
But he wouldn’t do that.
He felt it was normal to sit there and watch me doing these things.
I was embarrassed.
Even when I bought my car, I would wash the car myself.
And he would be there but not help me to do it.
My neighbours would wonder, “You have a son, why can’t he do those things for you?”
I would go and fetch water by myself when there was no water in the house.
That worried me so much.
Even the car, I only used it for three months, before he destroyed it.
He would just take the key without my permission, drive out and end up damaging the car.
He would bring it back like that and then disappear.
I would then need to repair the car.
After repairing it, he would cry and say that something pushed him to do it and he did not know
how he took the key and drove the car out when I told him that he should not do that.
I told him I would buy another car that would be his; I asked him to be patient and wait till I bought another car.
But each time I travelled a long distance and didn’t need to drive, he would take the keys and go out with friends,
his dance group and the car would get damaged.
There was a time the exhaust pipe came off completely where he parked it and they towed it away.
I came back and he ran away for two days.
I told him to keep running, that he should not come back to my house anymore.
I told him to stay away because he was giving too much stress.
Sometimes I would ask him if he came to destroy me.
I used to ask him this question.
He wouldn't know what to answer me.
It is not that he was bad in other areas.
I never saw him bringing women to the house, smoking or drinking and getting drunk.
He would just stay indoors.
Recently, I bought him computers since he does not like going out
so he could work on the computers by himself.
Recently, his group went for "Nigeria's Got Talent"; they almost got to
the first position but it was taken away from them.
I noticed that any time he touched electronic items, they would be destroyed.
Recently, what made me so angry was – I bought a sewing machine
and I wanted to sew something for myself for my work.
I did not know he had gone to my room.
The key of my room was not working so I did not lock it when I travelled.
I bought the material to sew the items and when I wanted to start,
I noticed that the machine was no longer working.
I asked him what had happened and he said he had wanted to use the machine to sow something for himself
and the machine just broke.
I got so angry and said that I would not take it any longer.
That was why I said that when I got to Lagos after work, I would come to The SCOAN and
the God of T.B. Joshua must do it for me.
Don't worry, you are in the presence of God.
He also talked about a baby girl.
Yes.
What can you say about that?
Yes, that was my last born child after him.
They were so close when she was little.
They would dance together and do things together a lot.
They really liked each other.
When she was nine years old, she became very ill and developed leukemia.
I don't know where it came from.
She was taken to the hospital while I was not around.
They said that they needed blood for her and I had told them not to give blood to my children
when I was not there for screening.
So, they did not get any blood for her and that was what killed her.
After she died, he would tell me that she lived in his room, wore his clothes
and went somewhere – that was when he was in secondary school.
He said he would see her taking his clothes; this was after she had died.
He said she would take his clothes, put them on and then go out.
I was worried about that and did not know what was going on.
You evil spirit, how did you enter this body?
From his sister.
The day his sister died, he lay on top of her.
He wanted to give her life; I came into him.
You have a beginning and you have an end; your end has come.
All over your body, Holy Ghost Fire!
Fire, in the name of Jesus Christ!
Come out of this body!
Out, you prince of Persia.
Out of this body, in the name of Jesus Christ!
Out, in the name of Jesus Christ.
Out!
You wicked queen.
Out, in the name of Jesus Christ!
Out!
In Jesus' name. Amen.
Stand up.
How are you?
I'm fine, sir.
Come.
What happened to you? Why are you like this?
Maybe I was sleeping.
Who removed your tie and your jacket?
Who removed it?
I don't know.
This is your mother.
Yes.
She's my mum.
And this is your uncle?
Yes.
Good.
Can you remember what you said?
What did I say?
I don't understand.
Maybe I have to remind you.
You said that you were the prince of Persia and that you were a queen from the marine world.
No, it's not me.
You can see from his present confession that the demons that were speaking through him in the past,
by the grace of God, Jesus has cast them out.
So, right now, he is a new person.
Thank You, Jesus!
So, no one should use what he has said and done in the past against him, otherwise the person will be tempted
and we pray you will not be tempted, in Jesus' name.
Thank You, Jesus!
Children of God – Emmanuel!
(God with us – Matthew 1:23)
My name is Samuel Freedom, I am from Imo State, Nigeria.
On my right is my uncle who is a pastor.
This is my mother who is a renowned Nollywood actress.
I was in my office one afternoon when my uncle-in-law told me that he saw my mum on Emmanuel TV
and the man of God had asked her, "Where is your son?"
and that she said that her son was in the house in Enugu.
Later that day, I received a call from my mum; she said that I should come to Lagos,
that the man of God wanted to see me.
I knew and had no dispute that my time had come.
I knew the reason why God wanted me to come here.
I knew I had to be delivered from certain things that were disturbing and troubling my life.
Before I came to The SCOAN, many people had told me
that this was not a house of God,
that they manipulate people and hypnotize them to say things that they were not supposed to say
and that I shouldn't go there.
I said, "No, my time has come".
I knew that if I came here I would be delivered and saved from whatever that was troubling me.
When I came to The SCOAN, Wise Man Christopher laid his hand on me.
The evil spirit that was in me started to confess a lot of things that were troubling and manipulating my life.
After the deliverance, there were a lot of changes that I noticed in my life.
I have been transformed.
I see people in a different way.
I communicate better.
I see that I am humble; there is humility in my life now, unlike before.
I never used to take instructions; I would be so disobedient but now, I even do the dishes.
I hated doing the dishes – I saw it as a task.
But now I sweep, clean-up the whole place and keep it tidy.
I can now hear God speaking clearly to my spirit.
There have been a lot of transformations.
I am so happy to be here.
I thank God that my life has changed.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus!
Just to reflect back to the past, so that we can have a very good reason
to praise the Lord for this great deliverance.
We know you have come a long way before this deliverance.
Can you please tell us a little bit about your past and how this evil spirit had tormented your life?
OK.
Before I came here, I was an evangelist.
I had started going to people's houses to evangelise and preach to many,
to get them saved, born again and to lead them to Christ.
I would pray for the sick and things would happen.
It got to a point where the enemy had come in.
There was a woman I had an affair with in the church.
There was something we did that stopped the Spirit of God from flowing in my life.
My prayers were no longer answered and wherever I went, anything I put hands to was no longer prospering.
OK. You mean that while you were praying for people, preaching to them, delivering them,
you had an affair with a sister in the church?
Yes.
That was where the problem started from?
OK, continue.
I went to my village because my grandfather was blind, so I went to pray for him to receive his sight.
I fasted for a month but when I got there, nothing happened; there was no power.
I got frustrated.
I was depressed.
The enemy used that as an opportunity to come into my life and channelled me into doing other things,
to keep myself happy.
I felt so sad; I wanted to commit suicide.
Sometimes, I would hear a voice that would tell me, "Jump".
Where we live, we live in a high tower and sometimes, I would hear a voice telling me "Jump"
but I would try to hold myself.
Before I knew what was happening, I diverted the gifts I used to have before I was transformed -
I used to be a rapper, I used to sing and dance - I started doing those things.
I returned back to them and I was going for competitions, such as Malta Guinness Street Dance.
I used to dance in the church because I was in the choir but diverted it into street dance - worldly kind of dances.
When we got there, we lost in the first competition, which was the Malta Guinness Street Dance.
We went out for Nigeria's Got Talent; we had to upgrade what we had.
We started to try and get inspiration from so many places.
We used the internet to download new stuff.
In the process, I came across an illuminati webpage which said that the only way you could get famous
was by joining this group.
I wanted to know more things about them.
I went through their webpage and saw everything concerning them, including their procedures.
I also saw their master.
Surprisingly, it got to a stage whereby I was sleeping and the master came to me in my dream to speak to me.
The first time he came, he appeared as a serpent; he was looking for me.
He asked, "Where are you?"
You mean that was a demon you had contact with?
Yes.
He came to me in the dream; he was looking for me and I was running away.
When he got to me, the serpent was speaking to me but I couldn't understand what it was saying.
So, I asked him to try and talk to me in a human form, in a way that I could understand what it was saying.
Then, it transformed into a human being and it was exactly the face I had seen on the webpage.
It started giving me instructions on what to do and things I should carry out.
Before I knew it, I started getting inspirations and I didn't know where they came from.
I started using this move we call 'the tut', where you use your hands to make shapes.
It came from Egypt; his name was 'King Tut'.
We now looked for a way to use those symbols and signs from the illuminati to form a dance move.
When we did these dance moves, people didn't really understand it,
they'd think it's just a dance move, it's a step but they didn’t know that
they were being drawn into that kingdom.
The more they would see the signs, the more they would do it, the more they would become loyal to the enemy.
You mean the inspiration you got from the demons, you put them into practice in your dances.
People would see it as an ordinary dance move but they wouldn't know that this was from the evil world,
and this influenced people and got them initiated.
Yes.
They would say, "Ah, where did you get these moves from? They're cool.
We would like to join you, so you can teach us more".
So, we opened a dance academy and were bringing more souls into the kingdom of darkness
to teach them these moves that they had hunger to learn.
We went out there, dance in the clubs, we'd have shows; the more people watched these things,
the more the enemy came to torment them in their dreams, programmed them to act the way we would act.
Even our dressing says a lot, the way we dress.
Thank God, when I came to The SCOAN, there was a dress I was supposed to put on, I loved it so much,
it had the symbol and the sign of the illuminati.
My mum would always tell me, "Don't dress that way; don’t look that way.
You have clothes and suits, try to put them on. It's not good".
I had to dress normally.
In other words, you mean that the kind of dress you put on and the signs and symbols on them
should not be overlooked, and they mean more than their ordinary look - is that right?
Yes, they influence your subconscience.
Before you know what is going on, you will start seeing them everywhere you go, anything you think.
Whatever anyone does, you would say, "That is the sign".
You start seeing demons everywhere you go.
My coming to The SCOAN has brought me back.
Thank God the man of God took us to the prayer mountain where we stayed, prayed and fasted.
Ever since then, my memory has come back and now I have more understanding about the things of God.
Shall we clap for Jesus Christ!
During your deliverance the evil spirit identified itself as a "prince of Persia".
Tell us, when did you notice that the evil spirits had come into your life?
There was a video game I had in my house, sometimes, I played it just to keep myself busy;
it's called 'The Prince of Persia'.
I had the movies in my house and used to watch them and played the game.
Before I knew what was happening, I started seeing myself
doing the same things that the character in that game was doing.
I saw myself fighting with a sword in the spirit, flying, doing a lot of things that I never knew
I could do in my dreams.
It started affecting me physically.
I started to want to fly and do the same things in the physical realm.
So, we had to put those things into our dance moves.
We would 'fly'.
We wouldn’t stay on the ground; we hated the ground.
We kept 'flying' up and down everywhere.
We did a lot of things that were frightening to people but they loved it, it was entertaining to them.
So, I would like to advise people, who watch movies, they should be careful of what they watch
because it influences our minds and lives, without you even knowing it.
The evil spirit also said it led you to so many other things, like masturbation and others...
Can you tell us why you were doing all these things?
Were you conscious of what you were doing at that time?
It was the evil spirit that made me to do it.
I couldn’t have done it out of my own, it was the evil spirit that forced me.
Each time I did it, I would regret.
I kept crying, "God, deliver me, save me from this. When am I going to stop this?
OK, after this one, this will be the last time I do it".
But I would still find myself doing those things without knowing what was the cause of it.
I thank God everything is over now.
You no longer see all those things and characters you used to see in your dreams. Do you?
I no longer see them.
I used to hear voices that would tell me to go and deceive people.
The more you did it, the more famous you'd get, in a sense.
Those voices, I don’t hear them anymore; they are gone now.
I only hear the Spirit of God speaking and telling me, "Study, pray more, fast and carry out
the character of Christ. Show them the foundation doctrines of Christ,
that is all I want you to do here on earth".
We thank God Almighty for your life.
Now that you are totally delivered, we want to encourage you to remain in faith in Christ Jesus.
It is not enough for us to come and receive deliverance but we must also remember that we need to submit
totally to the will of our Lord Jesus Christ.
Make His Word the standard for your life so that the deliverance you have received
will be permanent, in Jesus' name.
I want to advise our parents that whatever you don’t want your little kids to know,
you should not allow those things to hang around in the house.
Take them away and don’t even use them.
There is something that demons can do, they will lead kids to find those things wherever you hide them.
Even if it is inside your bag, they will still go there and find those things.
The Bible says, train up a child in the way he should go and when he is old, he will not depart from it.
When they watch those things, it influences them.
I have a message for teenagers and youth.
Mind the kind of things you download into your phone.
Do away with worldly music.
Do away with anything that does not have the symbol of God on it.
Now in my phone, I do not have any worldly music;
I deleted everything that concerns the enemy.
All I have in my phone now, is Gospel music -
things that speak to me more about God, that bring me closer to God.
I believe that when we do away with these things, the enemy has no power over us.
I also have an advice for pastors: keep praying, never say, "Let us just do this, God is a forgiving Father.
He will have mercy when we do this and pray about it. He is a merciful God, He is going to forgive us our sins".
That was how all these things started.
Once you fall into sin, the enemy does not waste a split second to come into your life and begin to manipulate it.
For those who have the angels like Gabriel, who have been praying for an answer, and have not received
an answer from God yet; I would advise you to come to The SCOAN.
Although there are other churches but I believe the anointing of God's Spirit is strong and thick in this place.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus.
Thank you very much for acknowledging that The SCOAN is not the only living church.
We have many living churches out there.
Just like you have advised - people should pray that the Spirit of God Almighty
should direct them to a living church, where they can fellowship with people of God
and where their faith can be encouraged to grow.
Thank you for the wonderful advice you have given.
There is something you didn't say.
Tell us, what was your experience the moment you came face to face with the wise man.
What happened when the wise man touched you?
OK.
When he touched me, I felt like fighting and attacking him.
Before I knew what was happening, I became weak and I didn't know what was happening around me.
I felt power surging through my body everywhere, I felt something I had never felt in my entire life.
Thank God, I am free.
I have been set free.
I am delivered.
Now, I can use my gifts to preach the Gospel and minister to the people of God.
I am free.
Thank You, Lord Jesus.
Let us clap for Jesus Christ!
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe, to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances, sermons and testimonies
from The Synagogue Church Of All Nations.
Emmanuel TV – changing lives, changing nations and changing the world.